

# **Eric Cross** / UX and Product Design

### www.ericxcross.com eric.cross@sympatico.ca +44 7935 673288

Designer and developer based in Edinburgh, UK / Recent graduate of a 16 week software development course at CodeClan / Past experience as an industrial designer / Successful freelancer / Passionate athlete Looking for new opportunities in UX and digital product design.

# **Selected Projects**



#### **ALZHEIMER'S SCOTLAND / ALEXA APP AND DESIGN GUIDELINES**

UX Designer at Codeclan / 3 weeks in June 2019

Development of an Amazon Alexa application and guidelines for creating assistive technologies for users with alzheimers and dementia. Ongoing development includes indepth user research, an audit of their current UX, and user testing with carers and dementia sufferers.



#### CODECLAN / TREETRIP WEB APPLICATION

Group Project with Alasdair Carstairs and Miriam Boran / 1 week in May 2019 A CO2e calculator that helps people understand the environmental impacts of their travel. Developed in a one week sprint using NodeJS / MongoDB / WebPack / HTML / CSS.

case study available at www.ericxcross.com/treetrip



#### PROFIM / SEATING DESIGN STRATEGY

Product Designer at ITO Design / June 2017 - November 2018
Strategic multi-product seating development to accommodate new use environments such as home office, co-working and hot desking spaces.
Roles included market research, workshop facilitation and product design.
case study available at www.ericxcross.com/ellie



#### MCDONALD'S / SELF SERVE CUSTOMER EXPERIENCE

Freelancer for Blue Sky / April - June 2016

A new customer journey to transition restaurants to digital (self-serve) ordering. Roles include research, wireframing of current experience and creating guidelines for new flow, zoning, and digital kiosk placement. **case study available at** www.ericxcross.com/mcdonalds-experience

### **Education**

#### CODECLAN

#### **SQA PDA IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT (LEVEL 8)**

Edinburgh, UK Feb - June 2019 16 week intensive software development course to develop industry relevant programming skills. Agile structure with 4 weeks instructor led classroom learning interspersed with 1 week project sprints.

#### **CARLETON UNIVERSITY**

#### **BACHELORS OF INDUSTRIAL DESIGN**

Ottawa, Canada Sept 2011 - June 2016 Four year degree with course requirements in psychology, business and design. Undergraduate thesis conducted with Herman Miller to issues around for supply storage and administration in Canadian ICUs. Awarded the Provost Scholarship for academic research in 2016.

### **Professional Experience**

#### **SELF-EMPLOYED**

#### **FREELANCE DESIGNER**

Currently Edinburgh, UK Feb 2015 - Ongoing

Experienced freelancer and subcontractor for projects in healthcare, furniture, spacial design, and tech. Services include market research, usability research, speculative design, experience design, concept development, and design for manufacture.

#### ITO DESIGN INDUSTRIAL DESIGNER

Cham, Switzerland June 2016 - Sept 2018

Studio specializing in design for the office environment. Part of a small team researching and developing new products from conception to production. Directly involved in client interactions and project management. Focus on usability and functional innovations in the ergonomic furniture and seating markets.

#### **OTI LUMIONICS**

#### **DESIGN INTERN**

Toronto, Canada May - Aug 2015 Startup in the OLED manufacturing industry. Roles included designing OLED lighting concepts, creating retail and brand engagement pieces and content design for the OTI and Aerelight website.

#### BLUE SKY

#### **EXPERIENCE DESIGN INTERN**

Sydney, Australia June - Dec 2014 Consultancy focused on customer experience and spatial design. Heavily involved in a branch transformation project for ANZ bank in Australia. Conducted secondary research, site visits, supplier surveys, user flows, spatial diagrams and facilitated design workshops. Continued freelancing for Blue Sky on related projects until 2016.

## Software / Skills

**Design** Adobe XD / Photoshop / Illustrator / InDesign

**Software Dev** JS / Java / Ruby / Processing / HTML / CSS

**Frameworks** React (JS) / Express(JS) / Spring (Java) / Sinatra (Ruby) / Webpack(JS)

**Databases** PostgreSQL / MongoDB

Versioning

Git / GitHub

3D Modelling Languages Rhino 3D / Solidworks / Grasshopper (algorithmic) / T-Splines (Sub-D)

English (Native) / French (Professional Working Proficiency) /

German (Elementary Proficiency)

### Links

**Portfolio** www.ericxcross.com

**LinkedIn** www.linkedin.com/in/ericxcross **GitHub** www.github.com/ericxcross



#### **Eric Cross**

**UX and Product Design** eric.cross@sympatico.ca +44 7935 673288